Robert Garrett Collection of Ethiopic Manuscripts, 1600s-1900s: Finding Aid C0744.03
Manuscripts Division
- Series 1: Robert Garrett Collection of Ethiopic Manuscripts (C0744.03), 1570-1950; 82 boxes; 39 items
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 74: Psalter, 1670-1899; 74; 1 box Parchment. 190 folios, 1 column [fols. 1r-177r], 2 columns [fols. 178r-186r], 13-16 lines. Hide covers, stitched with open spine. Folios 1r-3v and 26v are blank. 9.5 x 10.0 cm
    - Song of Songs, late 17th century; 1 box Folio 173r-181v (Box 74)
    - Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām) Marked for the Seven Days of the Week, late 17th century; 1 box Folio 182r-190v (Box 74)
      (incomplete, end missing)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 75: Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām), 19th century; 75; 1 item Parchment. 50 folios, 1 column, 9-10 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine, double skin case with strap. Fols. 1r-2v and 47v-50v are blank 7.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 75)
    Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām) marked for the seven days of the week, fols. 3r-47r.
    Fls. 49v and 50v have writing in pencil, mostly consisting of magic names.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 76: Fragment of the Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām), late 19th century; 76; 1 item Parchment. 20 folios, 2 columns, 12-14 lines. Cardboard covers (back cover with marbling) with drawings and pen trials, stitched with cloth spine. 9.5 x 12 cm (Box 76)
    Fragment of the Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām), for Saturday and Sunday, fols. 1r-20v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 77: Liturgical Miscellany, 1870-1899; 77; 1 box Parchment. 61 folios, 1 column, 13-19 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine 11 x 13 cm
    Folios 1r-2v and 60r-61v are cut from an earlier manuscript of the Book of Acts.
    - Kidān Zanagh or Morning Covenant, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-23v (Box 77)
    - The Anaphora of Our Lord Jesus Christ ('Akwatēta Kwerbān Za'egzi'ena 'Iyasus Krestos), late 19th century; 1 box Folio 23v-36v (Box 77)
    - Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), late 19th century; 1 box Folio 36v-59r (Box 77)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 78: Liturgical Miscellany, 1830-1870; 78; 1 box Parchment. 64 folios, 1 column, 14 lines. Parchment covers, stitched with open spine, skin case. Folios 1r, 2v, 3v, and 64v are blank 7 x 10 cm
    Former owner: Sehina Sellāsē.
    - Prayer of Supplication to Jesus Christ Incorporating Passages From the Gospels for the Salvation of Body and Soul, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 5r-26r (Box 78)
    - Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 26v-34r (Box 78)
    - Psalm 119 (Ethiopian Recension), mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 34r-46r (Box 78)
    - Discussion on the Ten Commandments, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 46r-48v (Box 78)
    - Prayer of Mary at Golgotha for Yakkātit 16, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 48v-54r (Box 78)
    - Kidān Zanagh or Morning Covenant, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 54v-63r (Box 78)
    - List of the Days When Heaven Is Open to Receive Prayers (rehwa samāy) and the Annual Feast Days of the Apostles, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 63r-64r (Box 78)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 79: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), late 19th or early 20th century; 79; 1 item Parchment. 28 folios, 1 column, 12-13 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine, double hide case covered with stamped tan leather. Fols. 1r-2v, 27r-28v are blank 6.5 x 8.5 cm (Box 79)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", fols. 3r-26r.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 80: Lenten Antiphonary (S'oma Deggwā) Fragment, second half of the 19th century; 80; 1 item Parchment. 26 folios, 1 column, 15-19 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine 8 x 11 cm (Box 80)
    Fragment of the S'oma Deggwā or Lenten Antiphonary, with cantillation signs in the three different modes, fols. 2r-25v.
    Endnotes: a short prayer, fol. 25v; a magic prayer, fol. 26r; pen trials, fols. 1r-v, 26v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 81: Grammar Book (Sewāsew), second half of the 19th century; 81; 1 item Parchment. 50 folios, 2 columns, 13-17 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Blank leaves 41r-42v 8 x 11 cm (Box 81)
    Ge'ez grammar book (Sewāsew) in Amharic, fols. 3r-48v; interrupted by a list of magic names, fols. 40r-41r, blank leaves 41r-42v, and continuing fols. 43r-48v.
    Scribe: Walda Māryām.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 82: Collection of Malke' Hymns, 1830-1870; 82; 1 box Parchment. 69 folios, 1 column, 10-15 lines. Wooden boards (split and repaired, loosely stitched with open spine. 9 x 10 cm
    Fols. 1r-v, 4v-5r, and 68r-69v are blank except for pen trials and ink smudging.
    - Malke' Hymn to the Virgin Mary, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 2r-22r (Box 82)
    - Malke' Hymn to Jesus Christ, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 22r-38r (Box 82)
      Fols. 23-24 are bound sideways and contain part of a different malke' hymn.
    - Malke' Hymn to St. Michael, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 38v-48v (Box 82)
    - Malke' Hymn to St. Gabriel, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 48v-54r (Box 82)
    - Malke' Hymn to 'Aragāw, One of the "Nine Saints", mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 54r-61r (Box 82)
    - Malke' Hymn to St. Gabra Manfas Qeddus, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 61r-64v (Box 82)
    - Salām Hymn to the Assumption of the Virgin Mary, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 64v-68r (Box 82)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 83: Anaphora of the Virgin Mary, Doctrina Arcanorum, 1870-1899; 83; 1 box Parchment. 60 folios, 1 column, 11-14 lines. Wooden boards, with printed cloth cover. 7 x 10 cm
    Endnotes: a prayer against smallpox and measles, fols. 47r-48r; an incomplete contract note, fol. 60v.
    Folios 1r-2v are blank except for pen trials.
    Former owner: Walda Sellāsē.
    - Anaphora of Our Lady Mary ('Akwatēta Qwerbān Za'egze'tena Māryām) by Abba Heryāqos (Cyriacus) of Behensā, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-46r (Box 83)
      Also sometimes called Qeddāsē Māryām.
    - Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), late 19th century; 1 box Folio 49r-58v (Box 83)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 84: Psalter, 1830-1870; 84; 1 box Parchment. 105 folios, 1 column [fols. 1r-80r], 2 columns [fols. 81r-105r], 15-16 lines. Wooden boards (front board partly missing, back board split and repaired, stitched with open spine. 11 x 11 cm
    Endnotes [all later hands]: a note of ownership on paper in the name of Asfāw, son of Mamrē (sic) Kidāna Māryām, fol. 2v. a Mawāse't fragment, fol. 80v; a short chronology in Amharic from Adam through King Tēflos (i.e. Tēwoflos, r. 1708-11), fols. 102v-104r; another Mawāse't fragment, fols. 104r-105r.
    Former owners: 'Arkaselus (?) and his son Bas'aggā Walda Yohannes.
    - Psalms, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 2r-54v (Box 84)
      Incomplete (beginning at Ps.101).
    - Canticles of the Prophets, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 55r-71v (Box 84)
    - Song of Songs, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 71v-80r (Box 84)
    - Praise of Mary (Weddāsē Māryām) Marked for Each Day of the Week, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 81r-95v (Box 84)
    - Gate of Light ('Anqas'a Berhān, the Secon, Shorter office of the Virgin Mary, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 95v-102r (Box 84)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 85: Prayer of Mary at Golgoth, Doctrina Arcanorum, 1870-1899; 85; 1 box Parchment. 28 folios, 1 column, 15-24 lines. Wooden boards (front board mostly missing), stitched with open spine. Fols. 27r-28v are blank. 6 x 10.5 cm
    Fragment.
    Endnote: a prayer (text stained and partly illegible), fol 1r-v.
    - Prayer of Mary at Golgotha for Sanē 21, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 2r-20v (Box 85)
    - Prayer for Binding Demons, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 21r-24r (Box 85)
    - Fragment of the Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), late 19th century; 1 box Folio 24v-27r (Box 85)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 86: Divine Office (Deggwā), mid 19th century; 86; 1 item Parchment. 92 folios, 2 columns, 12 lines. Hide covers 9 x 10 cm (Box 86)
    Deggwā containing hymns and troparies for the Divine Office, with some cantillation signs (beginning missing, opening in abrupto), fols. 1r-92v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 87: Collection of Magico-Medical and Divination Texts, 1830-1870; 87; 1 box Parchment. 77 folios, 1 column, 18-22 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine 7.5 x 10.5 cm
    Endnotes [various hands]: fidal (1st order syllabary) and number signs, together with a magic prayers, fol. 10r; commands for overcoming evil spirits, fol. 10v; magic figures and a prayer against rheumatism, fol. 46r-v; prayer against various ailments, fols. 46v-47v; various magical prayers, fols. 73r-77v.
    - Mirror of Solomon (Mas'hēta Salomon), a Magico-Medical Work Giving Various Prescriptions and Procedures, Partly in Amharic, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-7v (Box 87)
    - Computation of Aristotle the Wise (Hassāba T'abib 'Arest'āt'ālis), A Magic Work for Overcoming Enemies, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 7v-9v (Box 87)
    - Computation of the Stars (Hassāba Kawākebt), an Astrological Work for the Twelve Signs of the Zodiac, Partly in Amharic, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 11r-46r (Box 87)
    - Computation of Qalamsis (Hassāba Qalamsis), a Magico-Astrological Treatise, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 48r-72r (Box 87)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 88: Malke' Hymn to Abbā Sāmu'ēl, second half of the 19th century; 88; 1 item Parchment. 16 folios, 1 column, 13 lines. No covers, two loosely stitched and separate gatherings. Fols. 15r-16v are blank 7.5 x 10 cm (Box 88)
    Malke' hymn to Sāmu'ēl (probably St. Sāmu'ēl of Waldebbā), fols. 1r-14v.
    Former owner: Takla Haymānot.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 89: Anaphora of the Virgin Mary, second half of the 19th century; 89; 1 item Parchment. 19 folios, 1 column, 9-11 lines. No covers, stitched. Folio 10v is blank 8 x 10 cm (Box 89)
    Anaphora of [Our Lady Mary] ('Akwatēta Qwerbān), also sometimes called Qeddāsē Māryām, by Abbā Heryāqos (Cyriacus) of Behensā (incomplete, terminates in abrupto), fols. 1r-19v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 90: Anaphora of the Virgin Mary, late 19th or early 20th century; 90; 1 item Parchment. 56 folios, 1 column, 10 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Folios 1-, 56v are blank 7 x 10 cm (Box 90)
    Anaphora of Our Lady Mary ('Akwatēta Qwerbān Za'egze'tena Māryām), also sometimes called Qeddāsē Māryām, by Abbā Heryāqos (Cyriacus) of Behensā, fols. 5r-56r.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 91: Religio-Magical Prayers and Other Texts, 1800-1900; 91; 1 box Parchment. 52 folios, 1 column, 10-16 lines. No covers, stitched 7 x 9.5 cm
    Former owner: Ferē Takla Haymānot.
    - Prayer Known as Lessāna Sab' (the Tongue of Man) against the Evils of Men's Tongues, early/mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-19r (Box 91)
    - A Magical Prayer, early/mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 19v-20r (Box 91)
    - Acts of Moses, an Account of How Moses Escaped from the Hands of Pharaoh, His Enemy, early/mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 21r-46r (Box 91)
    - Salām Hymn to the Martyr Marqorēwos (Mercurius), early/mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 46r-52v (Box 91)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 92: Theological Miscellany, 1770-1830; 92; 1 box Parchment. 21 folios, 1 column, 13 lines. No covers, stitched 8 x 10 cm
    - Prayer to God With the Refrain "Praise to Thee" (sebhat laka), late 18th or early 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-10v (Box 92)
    - Book of Creations (Mas'hafa Fet'ratāt), an Exegetical Treatise on the Creation Story With Commentary in Amharic, late 18th or early 19th century; 1 box Folio 10v-21r (Box 92)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 93: Doctrina Arcanorum, second half of the 19th century; 93; 1 item Parchment. 12 folios, 1 column, 13 lines. Hide covers with printed cloth over-sleeve, stitched 6 x 8.5 cm (Box 93)
    Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), fols. 3r-12r.
    Fols. 1r-2v, 12v erasures.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 94: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), 19th century; 94; 1 item Parchment. 30 folios, 1 column, 12 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine, leather slipcase. Fols. 1r-2v, 27r-30v are mostly blank 6.5 x 9 cm (Box 94)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", fols. 3r-26v.
    Ink drawing of the Virgin and Child, fol. 27v
    Ink drawing of St. John the Evangelist, fol. 28r
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 95: Malke' Hymns to Mary and Gabriel, 1850-1899; 95; 1 box Parchment. 25 folios, 1 column, 11 lines. Wooden board back only, stitched, leather slipcase. Fols. 1r-3v, 24r-25v are blank 5.5 x 8.5 cm
    - Malke' Hymn to the Virgin Mary, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 4r-10r (Box 95)
    - Malke' Hymn to the Archangel Gabriel, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 10v-22v (Box 95)
    - Brief Invocation With Magic Names, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 23v (Box 95)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 96: Prayer of Mary at Golgotha and Other Prayers, 1850-1899; 96; 1 box Parchment. 44 folios, 1 column, 14 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Fols. 1r, 44r-v are blank 7 x 9 cm
    Former owner: 'Amata Giyorgis.
    - Various Short Prayers, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 1v-6v (Box 96)
    - Prayer of Mary at Golgotha for Sanē 21, Attributed to Abrokoro, the Disciple of St. John, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 7r-43v (Box 96)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 97: Prayer of Mary at Golgotha and Doctrina Arcanorum, 1850-1899; 97; 1 box Parchment. 64 folios, 1 column, 10-12 lines. Wooden boards, stitched, printed cloth over-sleeve 5.5 x 8.5 cm
    Pen trials on fols. 1r-2v.
    Former owner: Gabra Madhen.
    - Prayer of Mary at Golgotha for Sanē 21, Attributed to 'Abrokoros, the Disciple of St. John, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-42v (Box 97)
    - Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), late 19th century; 1 box Folio 43r-62v (Box 97)
    - Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), late 19th century; 1 box Folio 63r-64v (Box 97)
      (Beginning only)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 98: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), late 19th century; 98; 1 item Parchment. 26 folios, 1 column, 10-12 lines. Hide covers, stitched with open spine. Fols. 1r-2v, 26v are blank 6 x 9 cm (Box 98)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 99: Malke' Hymn to St. George, and Other Texts, 1830-1870; 99; 1 box Parchment. 63 folios, 1 columns [fols. 1-31], 1 column [fols. 32-63], 9-10 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine, skin case with cloth strap. 6.5 x 7 cm
    - Prayer to Mary, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-9v (Box 99)
      (beginning in abrupto, opening missing),
    - Malke' Hymn to St. George, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 10r-29r (Box 99)
    - Canticles of the Prophets, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 29v-62v (Box 99)
    - A Miracle of Mary, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 63r-v (Box 99)
      (beginning only, the end is stained and illegible)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 100: Malke' Hymn to the Virgin Mary, second half of the 19th century; 100; 1 item Parchment. 40 folios, 1 column, 8-10 lines. Wooden boards covered with stamped leather, with a printed cloth over-sleeve 6 x 8 cm (Box 100)
    Malke' hymn to the Virgin Mary, fols. 3r-38r.
    Fols. 1r-2, 38v-40v blank except for pen trials fol. 1r.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 101: Prayers to the Cross, 1830-1870; 101; 1 box Parchment. 40 folios, 1 column, 12 lines. No covers, stitched 7 x 8 cm
    - Prayer for Driving Away Evil Spirits, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-5r (Box 101)
    - Series of Prayers to the Power of the Cross, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 5v-40v (Box 101)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 102: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), late 19th century; 102; 1 item Parchment. 25 folios, 1 column, 10-13 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Fols. 2r-v are blank 6 x 8 cm (Box 102)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", fols. 3r-24v.
    Rough ink sketches, fols. 1, 25r-v, as well on the back board (both inside and out).
    Former owner: Gabra Krestos.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 103: Prayer and Legend of St. Susenyos, etc, 1850-1899; 103; 5 items Parchment. Folded scroll (2 pieces of parchment sewn together), 21 folds, 1 column. 4 talismanic drawings (all in ink with some red coloring). 6.5 x 150 cm
    Grid of 9 squares with alternating face and transverse cross design infill.
    Eight-pointed star design with central face.
    Another eight-pointed star design with central face and eye-motifs at the ends of the arms.
    Guardian figure with drawn sword above a naked demon.
    Former owners: Walatta Sārā and Walatta Yohannes.
    - Prayer and Legend of St. Susenyos for the Protection of Pregnant Women and Infants, second half of the 19th century; 1 item
    - Prayer of the Mighty (S'alota S'enu'ān), second half of the 19th century; 1 item
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 104: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), late 19th century; 104; 1 item Parchment. 22 folios, 1 column, 7-12 lines. No covers, stitched. Fols. 1r-v, 22r-v blank 5 x 8 cm (Box 104)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", fols. 2r-21v (incomplete).
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 105: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), second half of the 19th century; 105; 1 item Parchment. Parchment folded strip (format known as 'sansul' lit. "linked"). 2 pieces of parchment, 15 folds, each 6 x 7cm, 1 column, written on both sides, 16-17 lines. Wooden end-boards. 7.1 x 99 cm (Box 105)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq) Lefāfa Sed, the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead".
    Former owners: Kenfa Mikā'ēl and Sayfa Mikā'ēl.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 106: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), late 19th century; 106; 1 item Parchment. 34 folios, 1 column, 13 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Fols. 1r-2v are blank 5.5 x 8 cm (Box 106)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", fols. 3r-34r.
    Former owners: Hadara Mikā'ēl and Walatta Sanbat.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 107: Malke' Hymn to the Savior of the World, late 19th century; 107; 1 item Parchment. 32 folios, 1 column, 7-8 lines. No covers, stitched 6 x 7 cm (Box 107)
    Malke' hymn to Jesus as Savior of the World (Malke'a Madhānē 'ālam), fols. 1r-32v.
    Former owner: Walda Gabre'ēl.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 108: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), 1850-1900; 108; 1 item Parchment. 32 folios, 1 column, 8-10 lines. No covers, loosely stitched. Fol. 1r is blank 6.5 x 7 cm (Box 108)
    Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", fols. 1v-32v.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 109: Malke' Hymn to Na'akweto La'ab, 1850-1899; 109; 1 box Parchment. 20 folios, 1 column, 10 lines. Wooden boards with printed cloth over-sleeve, stitched. Fols. 1r-4v, 18r-20v blank 5 x 6.5 cm
    - Malke' Hymn to King Na'akweto La'ab, a Canonized 13th Century King of Ethiopia, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 5r-17r (Box 109)
    - Prayer to Na'akweto La'ab, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 17r-v (Box 109)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 110: Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), 1870-1899; 110; 1 box Parchment. 28 folios, 1 column, 10-11 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine 6 x 7.5 cm
    Fols. 1v, 28v blank except for small pen trials, fol. 1v.
    - Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefāfa S'edq), the Ethiopian "Book of the Dead", late 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-26v (Box 110)
      Fol. 1r title page, text proper beginning fol. 2r.
    - Short Statement in Amharic Concerning the Persons of God, late 19th century; 1 box Folio 27r-28r (Box 110)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 111: Prayer of Mary at Golgotha and Doctrina Arcanorum, 1850-1899; 111; 1 box Parchment. 58 folios, 1 column, 11 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with open spine. Fols. 1r-2v, 57v-58r blank 5 x 7 cm
    Pen trials fol. 58r.
    - Prayer of Mary at Golgotha for Sanē 21, Attributed to Abrokoro, A Disciple of St. John, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 3r-39v (Box 111)
    - Doctrina Arcanorum (Temherta Hebu'āt), second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 39v-56r (Box 111)
    - Prayer to Jesus Christ for Protection from Various Diseases, second half of the 19th century; 1 box Folio 56v-57r (Box 111)
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 112: Hymnal for the Feast of St. John (Zemmārē Za-Yohannes), 1830-1870; 112; 1 box Parchment. 35 folios, 1 column, 9-11 lines. Hide covers, stitched with open spine. Folios 3r-v, 34r-v, 35r-v blank 5 x 7 cm
    - Hymnal for the Feast of St. John (Zemmārē Za-Yohannes), mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 4r-33v (Box 112)
    - Fragments of Two Folios Containing Part of Acts 9, mid 19th century; 1 box Folio 1r-2v (Box 112)
      Cut from an earlier manuscript used as two flyleaves.
  - Garrett Ethiopic Manuscript No. 113: The Tongue of Man (Lessāna Sab'), mid 19th century; 113; 1 item Parchment. 26 folios and 2 part-folios forming part of the spine covering, 1 column, 9-16 lines. Wooden boards, stitched with parchment spine cover. Fols. 1r-3v, 26v-18v blank 4 x 5 cm (Box 113)
    Prayer known as Lessāna Sab' (The tongue of Man) against slander and the evils of men's tongues, fols. 4r-26r.